uh look forward to being here. So, it's
been a quick three weeks, you know,
since we've got here. We've done a lot
of things starting with hiring the
coaching staff. Uh feel very good about
the guys we brought offensively, some of
which were with me, some of which were
here already with the Titans, and then a
couple other pieces that have been on
some other teams. You know, we've met
with Borgo and his staff and went kind
of through the evaluation processes of
some of the things that we're looking
for position specific. uh not to get too
deep into the weeds with scheme. Um so
those have been productive. We've met,
you know, all morning every day uh with
the offensive coaches. And when you're
installing a new system, the the biggest
thing is to make sure that we're
communicating the same way and and
understanding the language that that
we're going to use. Uh that's been
productive. Uh we've watched a lot of
tape on installations of runs, on
passes, on RPOS's, on move the pockets.
Uh but again, we're a little bit far
away from the scheme conversation. It's
just the communication aspect of it. How
do we call a double team? What's the
quarterback signals look like. So those
have been productive. And then in the
afternoon, uh we spent a lot of time on
free agents. Um and getting, you know,
accustomed to what's going out there in
the market that will be available here
shortly. Uh so it's been a it's been a
good three weeks. It's been a lot of
work. Um, got to meet a lot of great
people in the building here from the
video department, equipment, um,
trainers, a lot of good people here in
this building. PR, I don't want to leave
those guys out. PR guys are outstanding.
Um, so it's been uh, it's been a good
three weeks. Been a lot of work. Um,
that's good. We're staying right next to
the facility for right now, so not a lot
of drive time. And uh, look forward to
being here. Grateful to coach Salah, to
Mike for giving me the opportunity and
look forward to working with you guys.
>> What kind of went into your decision
making process?
>> Well, you want to get the first one out.
>> Remember to say your name and your
>> Buck Rising 104. Nice to meet you. Nice
to meet you, too, coach. Uh, what kind
of went into your decision-m process on
this specifically given that you were
pretty in demand this offseason?
>> Yeah, I'd just say it felt like the
right fit uh with the right people. Um,
obviously have a relationship with with
Robert dating back to the New York days.
uh but his vision of of what he wants to
do and how he wants to do it. Uh Mike
and and the vision that he has. And then
ultimately Cam uh was was a big factor.
Have a lot of confidence in this young
man. Um I'm sure I'll get asked about
the the pre-draft process last year
which was about this time. Had a lot of
touch points with him. Uh meetings, 30
visits, um you know, going down to
Miami, dinner with him and his family.
So, there was a was a good relationship
built up leading up to the draft. Um, so
I look forward to work with him. I know
he's in the building rehabbing. Uh,
April can't come soon enough to get
going on on the offensive installation
part of it. Uh, but have a lot of
confidence in how he played both at
Miami, Washington State. And then he had
a whole year under his belt playing in
the National Football League and getting
accustomed to the speed of the game and
the timing. Um, and that's not an easy
thing for quarterbacks. So, just felt
like the right fit, Buck. and uh look
forward to being here.
>> Jill, Fox 17 Sports, Jill Jelnick, Fox
17 Sports. Nice to meet you, coach.
Piggyback on your conversation with Cam,
you mentioned you you've seen him get
gain confidence. What specifically about
his style of play, athleticism, and
skill set? It excites you the most when
it comes to building the offense around
him? Yeah. Well, we got a lot of work to
do with with everybody, but again, he's
a he's a young athletic quarterback who
has accuracy, who can make plays on the
move. He can do a great job of, you
know, the play doesn't look great and
then all of a sudden it looks great
because of his ability. He's smart. Um,
you know, I look forward to
communicating with him and building this
thing together along with the other
pieces that we have in play and the
pieces that we'll go get. But it'll be a
collective deal. This is obviously a big
piece to quarterback. I understand why
you're asking it, but it's it's someone
that I look forward to working with.
>> Terry McCormack with Main Street Media.
>> Hi Terry.
>> Um on on cam.
>> No high back.
>> Hi.
Um
>> your face is ready.
>> Yeah. There you go. Easily. But just
getting started.
>> Yeah. with Cam when you evaluated him
last year. How much of what you had in
mind that you would do with him last
year can you now bring in after seeing
him played on on film for a year?
>> Yeah, Terry, good question. You know,
that's something that we're going
through right now. We're not we're not
there yet schematic wise. Uh I've
evaluated all his Washington State tape,
all his Miami tape. I've watched the the
games that he played last year here.
That's going to be a work in progress.
You know, it's the end of February. we
have some time here. But, uh, again,
there's I think he can do a lot of
things. Uh, he's going to have to put
the work in, which I know he will, and
then we'll, you know, we'll do stuff
that he feels comfortable with. I think
that's important for for any
quarterback, but particularly for a
young quarterback. So, we're we're kind
of going through that right now, Terry.
Not to avoid your question, but we're
we're just not quite there yet.
>> Down to ESPN, uh, you're clearly your
impact on Josh Allen. was one of the
more significant changes and upgrades we
saw a quarterback make since coming to
the league. What were some of the things
you could pull from that experience in
2018, 19, 20, etc. to this opportunity
to work with K?
>> Yeah, I think every situation is unique.
Um, again, we've had some young
quarterbacks previously with obviously
Josh and Jackson at New York, but
everybody's different. I don't want to
just put him into a particular box. I
think the most important thing is to
first develop the relationship with the
young man and then get a feel for how
he's seeing the game. That's hard to do
right now when you're not, you know,
able to sit down and talk a lot of
football. So, I always like to see the
game through the quarterback's eyes. And
again, there's going to be mistakes out
there that I think he's made on tape
previous and he might have a completely
different answer. So, that communication
is really important. I learned that
dealing with Josh, dealing with Jackson,
but been around some veteran
quarterbacks. It's a hard position to
play. Uh it's it's easy to sit back
there and say, "What the hell did you do
that for?" Uh but until I can get that,
you know, communication with him and go
through these plays with a fine tooth
comb, iron out the details of it, um you
know, we're a little bit ways from that.
>> Having watched him Washington State,
Miami, etc., and last year, where are
you from a mechanic standpoint? Because
there was always a lot of talk about his
footwork and getting the base better,
etc. Yeah, I feel comfortable with with
Cam. Um, his ability to throw the
football, his athleticism. Everybody's a
little bit different in their drops.
Everybody's a little different with
their throwing motion, but I'm I'm
excited to to work with this young man.
>> Cory Curtis from News 2. Coach, when you
when you
>> One more time,
>> Cory Curtis from News 2. Listening to
your opening statement, you sound a lot
like a head coach.
>> I'm not.
>> Hiring staff me. Uh, how much Robert's
obviously given you a lot as offensive
coordinator that maybe a lot of other
offensive coordinators wouldn't get. How
much of that was you taking this job?
>> Yeah. Well, I would say this, you know,
I have a tremendous amount of respect
for the job that Robert has to do. Um,
from being in that, I'm very happy to be
where I'm at right now and to be part of
this football team as the offensive
coordinator. Uh, I'm always going to be
here for Robert, the rest of the staff,
but you know, that's a hard chair to sit
in. Uh, and having some experience
sitting in it will help me relative to
being the best teammate I can be for
this staff. And, uh, this is the place I
want to be. I'm excited to be here. I
look forward to working with this young
nucleus, working with Robert, and uh,
doing the best job I can do as the
offensive coordinator.
>> Paul Kuharski from Paul Kuharski.com.
Hi.
>> Got your own got your own.com, huh?
Dame, right? look forward to having you
read it.
>> Make sure I get those blocks.
>> Yeah.
>> What are the biggest challenges to kind
of stamping an identity on an offense as
you install it while figuring out who
who can do what?
>> Sure. The first question that I would,
you know, that I throw back to anybody
that uses the word identity is is what's
your definition of identity for you? Is
it plays or is it more this is how we're
going to play the game? because that's
the way that I look at it. So, I want to
make sure I'm answering your question
the way you need it.
>> Go to when you need to
get get a first down.
>> Best play on a call sheet. Uh, no, I I
would say this. I would say identity for
us is is playing smart, is playing
tough. You know, I know Robert used fast
and violent. I believe that's that's an
identity that you play with regardless
of is it a run, is it a pass, is it an
RPO. uh we have to be disciplined uh in
our approach. We got to minimize the
penalties that we've had. We got to have
the right attitude, which to me is a
team first positive attitude. We got to
put the right work in. We got to have
enough grit dealing with tough times um
on the field and then tough times off
the field. And we have to play smart.
So, talking about identity, Paul, that's
that's kind of where I lean to. The
plays are the plays. Everybody's got a
number of plays. We'll we'll kind of
figure that out as we go and and as we
add pieces. You know, sometimes there's
certain plays that look good with one
quarterback or with a skill set of
receivers, a tight end, an offensive
line. Uh, but our offensive line has to
set the identity of of playing tough and
playing smart. That's where it starts at
the line of scrimmage.
>> What's something that you maybe believed
about quarterback development 10 years
ago that's changed?
>> It's a good question. I I don't know how
much has has relatively changed in terms
of the development of a player. You
know, our job is to build relationships
with these guys, particularly the
quarterback for myself, but with the
other guys, unite a room, instill
confidence, lead them, and then
ultimately develop them. And there's
different ways to develop, but there's
mental development and there's physical
development, and that's what we're
charged with as a coaching staff to make
sure we're doing a good job with with
all of our guys, not just the
quarterback, of uh of developing these
players the way we need to.
>> I'm I'm Jim White with Tennessee
Titans.com. Talking about Cam in the
pre-draft process, everything you
learned about him during the course of
last offseason. What was what did you
like about his personality, how you guys
kind of jive together?
>> A lot. Uh, you know, I think he's got
some moxy to him. Uh, he's tough. He
holds himself to a high standard, which
is which is important for that position.
Everybody's going to look to that
position to to be the leader of the
group. And again, I wasn't around him
last year. I've only seen him a few
times here or there as he's going
through treatment. So, there's, you
know, I got a lot I got to dive into,
but the the meetings leading up to the
draft process, the the communication
that we had, the the kind of
personalities that we have, um, you
know, that that was a good fit.
>> Are you kind of a tough love type of
coach? How would you describe how you
attack him or not attack him, but teach
him?
>> Yeah, I'd say the first thing is to
build that relationship first. Uh, to
figure out everybody's a little bit
different. Everybody responds to
different things. I think that's
important for a quarterback too to know
the 10 other people around him in the
huddle and and how they respond. Some
people respond to, you know, tough love
like I, you know, my grandmother gave me
growing up. Some people don't respond to
that. So that's the challenge of a
leadership position, both offensive
coordinator and quarterback, to make
sure we really know our guys, what makes
them tick. And, you know, look, I think
it's well documented. I get pretty
heated at times. Um, that's that's who I
am.
>> Steve from News Channel 5. Welcome down.
Brian, Robert said in the introductory
press conference, one of the things he
liked about you is your offense is a
little bit different than the norm of
what so many teams are running without
opening up the playbook. Can you
describe a little bit of your philosophy
of what makes your offense a little
different?
>> Yeah, I think look, everybody's got a
lot of the same plays uh in the National
Football League. It's it's how you
window dress them. It's the tempo that
you want to play with. Again, we're not
there quite yet. We're we're kind of
learning how to speak the same language
with people in the room that have been
here. Some new pieces, you know, we want
to play fast. We want to play physical.
We want to play with a certain edge to
ourselves. We want to not lose the game
by doing dumb things. But those are the
foundational pieces relative to scheme
or motion or no huddle. You know, we
have all those things. I think it's
dependent upon how the players can
handle those things as well, too. Uh
it's no good putting in a bunch of stuff
if your players can't handle it. So,
we're, you know, looking forward to
getting these guys here as soon as they
can get here.
>> Hi, Coach Lauren Walsh from WSMV Channel
4. Um, I'm curious what your self
reflection process was like um post
Giants and leading to now to where you
said this was the exact position and
place you wanted to be.
>> Yeah, I think look, this is my 26th year
in the National Football League going
into it. You do that every year at
whatever stop you're at. I think the
most important thing is to be where your
feet are at. Uh and it's here at
Tennessee, you know, tighten up as as
they say. I'm excited to be here. I'm
looking forward to it. There's a lot of
things I've learned away, whether it was
a defensive assistant, a quarterback
coach, a receiver coach. You try to do a
better job the next place you're at. And
my role is to try to, you know, help our
football team be the best offense we can
be u under the direction of of Robert,
which I think is very important. Um to
take the lead from the head coach. Uh so
again, we're we're excited. I think all
the coaches downstairs are excited. I
did tell Randy Jordan, I said I would
get up here and say the sole reason why
I came to Tennessee is because Randy
Jordan was the running back coach. So, I
wanted to put that out for him. Um,
>> hey Brian, mix us with the Tennessee.
And when when you interviewed for the
head coaching job here, what were the
areas that you identified as this is
what I would want to fix? This is what I
think needs to change. Were there areas
like that that you
>> Yeah, I'd say uh thoughtful question.
Again, we're beyond that. Uh I
appreciate the question. I'm more uh in
tune with what it takes for for our
offense to get better. Uh that's a great
question for Robert. He got the job. Um
and you know, I'm here as the offensive
coordinator and I couldn't be more
excited about it.
>> If we gear it to the offense, then what
are the areas that you would identify
that first need to be address?
>> Still working on it. So, uh again, I
don't want to give you guys answers. and
then three like we we have a lot of work
to do as a staff. We've been meeting
together. Um you know, we've been
staying pretty late for an offseason,
which is usually the case when you're
taking over a new program. We're at the
beginning stages. Um but that that's
what's fun about this is is to go ahead
and and make sure we're able to meet the
players and watch the players do things
that we ask them to do and maybe they're
taught a little bit differently. So to
get into we definitely need to do this
or this is how we're going to be. It's a
little too early for that right now. Hi
Ryan, Eastston Freeze with a Toz Sports.
Nice to meet you. Nice to meet you.
Besides Cam, what were some of the
things about this offensive roster that
you saw and said and they've got this
going for them?
>> Yeah, look, it's a youthful roster for
the most part. Um, I know there's some
free agents that are that are coming up
right now, but you know, they got two
receivers that are tough uh that play
the game the right way. You know, DK
obviously special teams is well
documented, but has done some things on
the offensive side of the ball. you. I
think, you know, Spears and Pard are two
good running backs that that make yards
when they have the ball in their hands.
Um JC, you know, is a big strong, you
know, I like JC. Um I think he's a good
piece there to have at at right tackle.
Um so look, there's there's a number of
things right now, but again, to give you
an evaluation of every guy or this is
what we're going to do, this is how
we're going to be. I just I like the
vision that that Salah had and I like
the vision that Borgo had. Um, and
there's a good young quarterback that I
felt very good about um, leading up to
the draft and I think he lived a lot of
good things uh, last year and look
forward to trying to build off of that
and and maybe incorporate some things
that he feels good about. But, you know,
April can't come soon enough.
>> More broadly, separate separate of the
roster you're inheriting and the people
you're going to bring in, what what kind
of problems are NFL offenses trying to
solve? Now,
>> it's a broad question, Paul. I I think
>> like a narrow one.
>> Yeah. No, no.
Um, look, you're you're to be a good
offense, you have to be able to throw
the football when the defense knows
you're throwing it and be able to run
the ball when they they know you need to
run it. So all the challenge that come
with that, the identification in the
pass part of the game, whether it's two
minute, whether it's third down, when
you have to throw the football, you
know, the communication element of of
having everybody on the same page, not
just the quarterback and not just the
line, it takes 11. And then in the run
game, you know, that's something that we
talked about this morning as a staff who
went through some goal line and short
yardage things, you know, just to detail
those things out. And, you know, those
are going to be situations where most of
the time they know you're running it. uh
you have to do a good job of staying on
the same page. The looks that you're
getting now, Paul, it's advanced as it's
you know, you go back and look at 2000
tape, which we have some of that on on
the computer right now, showing my age,
but um you know, the vanilla looks that
you're getting, it's it's not always
vanilla. There's a lot of disguises and
you have to figure out ways to
neutralize that as an offensive staff
and then ultimately, you know, you have
to execute it on the field.
>> You had Calvin really uh at Alabama.
What are your thoughts on the the
possible opportunity? I know you're not
doing roster moves and stuff like that,
but the possibility of working with him.
What are your thoughts on that? And how
have you seen him progress from when you
had him in college?
>> Yeah, I would say that one I I and
appreciate the question, T. I'm not
going to answer roster
roster questions, but I do know I do
know Rid have a relationship with Rid.
Uh he was great for me at Alabama. He's
had a productive, you know, career in in
the National Football League and look
forward to working with him. pretty much
>> coach Chris Harris at WSMV here in
Nashville. Welcome, sir.
>> Thank you.
>> Um I'm curious as as a play caller who's
done it for so long,
>> what excites you most about implementing
your system, growing an offense from the
ground up and watching it blossom.
>> Yeah. Well, the first thing is the
people. So, when you come into a new
building, the opportunity to meet a
variety of new people and gain new
insight on ideas. So guys like Luke
Stalker who's been here I think is a
tremendous coach very very sharp for the
short time that I've been around him. Uh
Greg Lewis who was at you know Kansas
City and Baltimore and Isaac who was at
Pittsburgh. You know it's a blend. It's
not just you know I don't like to say
it's my off it's our offense and until
we really get around these these players
um you know it's good to get around and
talk ball talk shop and change a little
bit here or this is the way I've done it
for the last 20 years. Is there a better
way to do it? That's the the cool part
of this thing when you first get here,
spending a lot of time together with the
coaching staff and then ultimately when
the players get in, which is the most
fun, is trying to implement that and you
know, you watch it out on the practice
field, you put a thing in that you think
looks good for those guys, maybe it's
not as good, you get input from them. I
think that's important, particularly
from the quarterback position, and you
just hit it from the ground up and you
keep on building. And, uh, there's going
to be some bumps along the way. Uh but
you know building with the right kind of
people uh both coaching staff,
players, personnel, support staff. Uh I
think that's the cool thing about
starting out new. There's a lot of work
done. You know, there's never enough
time in a day in February and usually
you say that in October. Uh but that's
the cool thing about